Keep the room well-lit and watch from a distance, okay?
Huh?
[Gintoki was swallowed up by the alien that grew to a humongous size.]
[What is it that Umibozu saw as he searched for Kagura?]
Kagura!
(星海坊主)神楽～っ!!
["You Know What Happens if You Pee on a Worm"]
(星海坊主)神楽！
Kagura!
おい しっかりしろ!!
Hey! Get a hold of yourself!
黙って見てたのか…？
You bastards... Did you just sit there and watch?
(星海坊主)ﾃﾒｴら
黙って見てたのか？
After my daughter saved your lives... as she grew weaker and weaker...
(星海坊主)助けてもらっておいて
ｵﾚの娘が弱っていくのを…➡
黙って見てたのかって
聞いてんだよ｡
Did you just sit there and watch her die?
(ﾊﾀ皇子)ままま 待て！
だって こんな状況じゃ➡
W-W-Wait! In this situation, we couldn't call a doctor, even if we tried... Right, Jii?
医者 呼ぶにも…｡ なぁ じい？
(じい)ﾜｼに ふるな！
Don't pass it to me! I don't know what happened! I don't know anything!
知らん！ ﾜｼは知らん！
今日から ﾎﾞｹたから！
I'm still in shock!
Damn you!
ﾃﾒｴ!!
(神楽)ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ ﾀﾞﾒよ…｡
Pappy, don't. Not after I saved their lives.
せっかく 私 助けたのに…｡
(星海坊主)神楽！
もう 大丈夫だ！
Kagura! It's okay now!
Daddy's going to take care of you! You don't have to worry!
父ちゃんが助けてやるから
もう 安心しろ！
I've changed, haven't I?
私 変わったでしょ？
私の力
人を傷つけるだけじゃないよ｡
My strength is not just for hurting people. I can protect people too, now, uh-huh.
人を守ることも
できるようになったよ｡
もう いい｡ しゃべるな｡
Don't talk anymore!
When I did...I made so many friends.
(神楽)そういうふうにしたらね
いっぱい 友達できたよ｡
(神楽)もう 独りじゃないね｡
I'm not alone anymore.
The Yato fought, and fought, and destroyed themselves.
(神楽)戦って 戦って
夜兎 滅びたね｡
The Yato fought, and fought, and found themselves all alone.
戦って 戦って
夜兎 独りぼっちになったね｡
Pappy, big brother...everyone...
ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰも兄ちゃんも みんな…｡
The ones we have to fight are ourselves. If we don't...everyone will be all alone.
戦わなきゃいけないのは
自分自身ｱﾙ｡
このままじゃ みんな
独りぼっちになってしまうよ｡
(えいりあんの うなり声)
(星海坊主)ぐっ!!
うっ！
ぐはっ！
あぁ…！
ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ… うっ！
Pappy...
神楽！
Kagura!
神楽～っ!!
《銀ちゃん…｡
Gin...chan.
銀ちゃん…》
Gin-cha...
(銀時)でぇいっ!!
神楽～っ!!
Kagura!
《銀ちゃん…》
Gin-chan...
♪♪～
Damn earthworm monster! Let her go!
この みみず野郎！ ｿｲﾂを離せ!!
ｼｮﾝﾍﾞﾝ かけんぞ！
甘～いｼｮﾝﾍﾞﾝ かけんぞ!!
Or I'll...I'll piss on you!
(星海坊主)そんなことしたらなぁ
大事なところが 腫れあがるぞ！
Don't do that!
Your you-know-what will swell up!
Didn't your mother...ever teach you that?
母ちゃんに習わなかったか!?
よぅ 今さら
何をしにきた？ 若造｡
Aren't you a bit late to be showing up now, young man?
どのﾂﾗさげて
ここに来れたんだ ﾃﾒｴは｡
What brings you here?
祭りが大好きでね｡
I love spectacles. Don't you? Fires, fights and aliens are what Edo is famous for.
火事とｹﾝｶと えいりあんは
江戸の華ってな｡ 知らねえかい？
(星海坊主)知るか！
えいりあん以上に 不快な野郎だ！
All I know is...you're a pain in the ass!! Get lost.
失せやがれ！
うるせえ！ お前 腕が折れてるぞ｡
Shut up! At least I still have two arms!
病院 行け!!
お前が行け！ 風邪ひけ！
My one arm is worth three of yours!
お前は 風邪をこじらせろ！
お前が こじらせろ！
Oh yeah?! Well, three of mine are worth six of yours!!
学校を ２～３日 休んで
休みあけに ﾁﾔﾎﾔされろぃ！
(じい/ﾊﾀ)うわぁっ！
ぐわっ！
You should go home! Go to a hospital and get a new brain to go with your new arm!!
だから お前は 早く帰れって｡
病院 行って 早く➡
腕に ﾏｲﾅｽﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰつけてこい！
(星海坊主)誰が つけるか！
If I get a new brain, it'll be to bring one back for you!!
ﾏｲﾅｽなんて
あんまり使わねえじゃねえか！
どっちかっつうと ﾌﾟﾗｽがいい！
And I'm not going to a hospital for just an arm! My left arm was a prosthetic anyways.
(星海坊主)だいたい
腕の１本や２本で 病院なんざ！
もともと義手なんだよ
ｵﾚの左腕は！
Have them make you a prosthetic head while they're at it, you barcode-headed geezer!
ついでに 頭も作ってもらえ
すだれじじい！
(えいりあんの うなり声)
(爆発音)
(近藤)止めろ！ なんとしても
ここで くい止めるんだ!!
Stop it! Your reign of terror ends here!
(近藤)ﾔﾂらを
江戸の街にいれるな～！
Don't let them get into the streets of Edo!
(隊士)副長！ ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙの設備が
もう ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬなんですが！
Vice-chief! The terminal is coming apart!
They're not going to blame us, are they?
(隊士)これ
責任問題になりませんか!?
Who cares? We'll just say that the monster destroyed it.
(土方)知るか｡ 全部
あのﾊﾞｹﾓﾉが壊したことにするぞ｡
Viewers, did you hear that? Despite specific orders from the government, the Shinsen-
(結野ｱﾅ)ﾃﾚﾋﾞの前の皆さん
聞きましたでしょうか！
我々は 今 目の前で
不正が起こる瞬間を…｡
(ｶﾒﾗﾏﾝ)ぐはぁっ！
あぁっ あれを見ろ！
えいりあんが ひいてくぞ！
Look at that!
The alien is retreating.
やったぁ ｵﾚたちの勝ちだ！
We did it! We've won!
いや 違う｡
No, we haven't.
Wh-What's it doing?! The alien is wrapping around the ship!
(隊士)なんだ ありゃ！
えいりあんが 船に集まってくぞ！
何が起こっているのでしょうか？
あそこに いったい何が… あっ！
What's happening? What is going on over there?
Look! There's someone...!
(隊士)見ろ 誰かいるぞ！
(隊士)えいりあんの中心！
Right in the middle of the monster!
(隊士)えいりあんの中心で
何か叫んでる！ 何か叫んでるよ！
Amid a maelstrom of jaws, someone is yelling! They're shouting something!
(土方)星海坊主!?
Umibozu? That's...Umibozu! And that guy!
(土方)ありゃ 星海坊主だ！
それに 野郎も！
どけ！
(星海坊主)小便 かけんぞ！
Out of my way!
Or we're gonna piss on you!
あれが 星海坊主…
まるで ﾊﾞｹﾓﾉじゃねえか｡
That's Umibozu? He's like a monster.
(沖田)いやいや
旦那も負けてませんぜ｡
No, no... Boss is keeping up with his pace!
With them there, we can't just carelessly shoot. They'll be caught in the crossfire...
しかし あれじゃ
こちらも うかつに手が出せん｡
ﾔﾂらまで巻き込… ん!?
(土方)あれは… 幕府の軍艦｡
Those are...Bakufu warships.
It's Pops! Old man Matsudaira is here!
(近藤)とっつぁんだ！
松平の とっつぁんだ！
(近藤)破壊神 松平 片栗虎！
The god of destruction! Katakuriko Matsudaira!
(近藤)やばいって…
あのおっさんが通ったあとは➡
We've got trouble! After that old guy is done, only ashes will be left!
ﾁﾘも残らねえぞ！
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙも消しかねねえよ！
He'll take out the entire terminal!
だぁ～っ!!
たぁっ!!
おうおう…｡
(星海坊主)今頃 うるせえのが
ﾌﾞﾝﾌﾞﾝ たかってきたぜ｡
Looks like they've finally shown up for their photo op!
We've just about taken care of things here.
もう ほとんど
ｶﾀついたんじゃねえのか？
I've got to hand it to you, punk, for an Earthling, you're pretty good.
…にしても ﾃﾒｴ
地球人にしちゃ やるな｡
ﾃﾒｴに言われても
嬉しくねえよ ﾊﾞｹﾓﾝめ｡
That means a whole lot of nothing coming from you, monster.
片腕で よく ここまで
暴れられたもんだぜ｡
I'm amazed you fought this far with just one arm.
(星海坊主)ﾃﾒｴも 片腕じゃねえか｡
You only have one arm yourself.
For your own sake, go home. You'll die if you stay any longer.
悪いことは言わねえ 帰れ｡
死ぬぞ｡
I'd love to, but I don't see any exits around here.
帰りてえけど
どっから帰りゃいいんだ？
非常口も見当たらねえよ｡
I can't figure you out.
ﾃﾒｴの腹が読めねえ｡
神楽を突き放しておきながら➡
You pushed Kagura away, so what are you doing here? Why do all this?
なんで ここにいる？
なんで ここまでやる？
I'd like to know the same thing. Why did I come here?
ｵﾚが聞きてえくらいだよ｡
なんで こんなところに
来ちまったかなぁ ｵﾚは｡
Are you...
お前…｡
安心しな｡
Relax. I'm not planning on taking that loudmouth brat back with me.
あんな うるせえｶﾞｷ
連れ戻そうなんて腹はねえ｡
And of course, I'm not planning on dying either. It's just that...
もちろん 死ぬつもりもねえ｡
だが…➡
ｱｲﾂを死なせるつもりもねえよ｡
I'm not going to let her die.
ﾊﾊﾊ…｡
(星海坊主)おもしれえ…
おもしれえよ お前｡
Interesting. You're an interesting fellow.
I think I understand why Kagura likes you.
(星海坊主)神楽が気に入るのも
わかった気がする｡
But what can you do with only one arm?
だが 腕１本で 何ができるよ？
ｱﾝﾀも１本だろ｡
You only have one arm, too.
No, no...
(星海坊主)いやいや…｡
(銀時/星海坊主)
合わせりゃ ２本だ!!
Together, we've got two!
It makes me sick to do it, but I'll help you until we rescue Kagura!
胸ｸｿ悪いが 神楽 助けるまでは
協力してやるよ！
ありがたく思え 父さん！
Count your blessings, Pops.
I see... Thanks!
そうかい！ ｿｲﾂは ありがとよ!!
What's that? The ship's keel, it's...
なんだ？ 船の底が…｡
おい ありゃ…｡
H-Hey, it's...
Wh-What is that?!
(隊士)な… なんだ ありゃ!?
The nucleus. The core of the parasitic alien.
核だ…｡ 寄生型えいりあんの中枢｡
(星海坊主)こんな でけえのは
初めて見るが➡
It's the first one I've seen that's this huge.
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙのｴﾈﾙｷﾞｰを 過度に吸収し➡
It's absorbed an excessive amount of the terminal's energy and finally blew right through the ship.
肥大化し
船底を破っちまったようだ｡
あれをつぶせば
ｺｲﾂらを止められ… はっ！
If we smash that, we'll be able to stop this thing.
Ka...
か… 神楽!!
Kagura!
おわっ！
It swallowed her up!
おい 飲まれちまったぜ！
やばい…｡ このままじゃ
ｺｲﾂを仕留めることはできねえ｡
We've got a problem... We can't kill it now!
(星海坊主)ｺｲﾂをやれば
神楽も死ぬ｡
If we do, Kagura will die.
Attention!
(松平)聞け～！
All civilians in the terminal vicinity! Leave the area immediately.
(松平)ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙ周辺に留まっている
民間人に告ぐ！
(松平)ただちに
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙから離れなさい！
We are about to open fire on the alien! Vacate the area immediately.
(松平)今から えいりあんに
一斉放射を仕掛ける！
(松平)ただちに 離れなさい！
なんだと!?
Wha?!
What?!
Pops, wait! A civilian child has been sucked into the alien.
とっつぁん 待て！
民間人のｶﾞｷが １人➡
えいりあんに取り込まれている！
(松平)近藤… ｶﾞｷ１人の命と江戸を
同じ秤に かけるつもりか？
Kondo... Are you weighing the life of a single civilian with all of Edo?
人を救うってことはな➡
Our mission is to save as many lives as we can.
人を殺める以上の度胸が
必要なんでぃ｡
大儀を見失えば
救える命も 救えなくなるぞ｡
Would you risk your entire mission for just one of those lives? Don't be a wussy.
甘ったれてんじゃねえよ｡
しかし とっつぁん！
局長！ えいりあんが！
But, Pops!
Chief, the alien!
(近藤)ｸｿｯ
また 動き出しやがった！
Damn! It's on the move again.
ほ～ら みろ｡ おじさんの
言うことを聞かないから｡
You see what I mean? That's what happens when you don't listen to me.
な？ おじさんの言うことは
だいたい正しいんだよ｡
But Pops knows best, doesn't he? I'm made up of 80 percent correctness.
おじさんの80ﾊﾟｰｾﾝﾄは
正しさで できていま～す｡
You two go on home! You're in our way!
(松平)そういうことだからさぁ➡
お前らも 家に帰りんさい｡
ｼﾞｬﾏだ｡ ﾍﾟｯ！
行け…｡
Go.
This place will soon be a sea of flames.
(星海坊主)
もうじき ここは 火の海だ｡
You...aren't thinking of doing this alone, are you?!
ﾃﾒｴ まさか １人で…｡
(星海坊主)つくづく
情けねえ男だよ ｵﾚは｡
I'm a real loser. I'm called the fiercest there is, but I can't protect anything.
最強だ なんだと
言われたところでよ➡
何にも守れやしねえ｡
家族ひとつ…
娘 １人 守れやしねえんだ｡
Not my family... Not my only daughter... Nothing.
The Yato fought, and fought, and found themselves all alone.
((神楽:戦って 戦って
夜兎 独りぼっちになったね｡
戦わなきゃならないのは
自分自身ｱﾙ｡
The ones we have to fight are ourselves. If we don't...everyone will be all alone.
このままじゃ みんな
独りぼっちになってしまうよ))
これも 逃げ続けてきた代償か｡
This the price I have to pay for running away for so long.
すまねえ 神楽…｡
I'm sorry, Kagura...
せめて 最期は
お前と一緒に死なせてくれ｡
At least let me die together with you.
This is why daughters get mad at their fathers.
これだからよぉ 世の中の親父は
娘に煙たがられちまうのかねぇ｡
おとうさんよ ｱﾝﾀ ﾃﾒｴのｶﾞｷ １人
信じることができねえのかい？
Look dad, can't you even trust your own kid?
ｱｲﾂが こんなもんで死ぬﾀﾏだと
思ってんのかい？
Do you think she's so weak that a little thing like this'll kill her?
５分だ｡
５分だけ 時間を稼いでくれ｡
Five minutes. Just delay 'em five minutes for me.
ｵﾚを信じろとは言わねえ｡ だが！
I'm not asking you to believe in me. But...
ｱｲﾂのことは信じてやってくれよ！
At least believe in Kagura.
お前 なにを…！
What're you planning to do?!
♪♪～
《な… なんてﾏﾈしやがるんだ》
What a crazy thing to do...
♪♪～
(砲撃音)
どうすんだ？ 近藤さん｡
(近藤)ｸｯ…｡
What're we gonna do, Kondo-san?!
(松平)松っちゃん砲 発射用意！
Ready the Matsu-Blaster for firing!
Commissioner
(部下)長官！
(松平)いいから撃て｡
Never mind. Just fire.
(部下)いや
そうじゃなくて あれを…｡
No, it's not that...
Look at that...
(部下)ﾔﾂら
逃げるどころか増えてます｡
They didn't leave...
In fact, there are more of them.
なっ!?
What?
You dumb-asses! Can't you see this old guy?
(新八)ｷｻﾏら！ このおっさんが
目に入らねえか!!
今 撃ったら もれなく
このﾊﾞｶ皇子も爆死するぞ！
If you shoot now, this idiot prince will be blasted to death!
もれなく国際問題だぞ！
You'll have an international incident on your hands!
(じい)５分でいいから
待てって言ってんだよ ｺﾗ！
Just wait five minutes, that's all we ask!
Sure, what difference could five minutes make?
５分なんて すぐじゃん！
矢のごとしじゃん!!
ｶｯﾌﾟうどんでも作って
待ってろって言ってんだよ!!
Go make yourself some instant ramen while you wait!
ﾃ… ﾃﾒｴら…｡
Y-You people...
That girl saved us.
あの娘には世話になったんでな｡
撃たないよね？ これ｡
大丈夫だよね～？
They won't shoot, will they? We'll be all right, won't we?
ったく あの天然ﾊﾟｰﾏが！
That darn wavy head! If he was intent on coming, he should've said so at the start.
来るなら来るって
最初から言えってんだよ！
どうせ来ると思ってたけどね…
あまのじゃくが｡
Well, I knew he was going to come, anyway.
((神楽:私 変わったでしょ？
I've changed, haven't I?
(神楽)私 人を守ることも
できるようになったよ｡
I can protect people too, now, uh-huh.
(神楽)そういうふうにしたらね
いっぱい友達できたよ｡
When I did...I made so many friends.
(神楽)もう 一人じゃないね))
I'm not alone anymore.
Kagura...
神楽！ 起きろ!!
Wake up...
ぎ… 銀ちゃん｡
Gi...Gin-chan...
ほ～ら 酢昆布 食べちゃうぞ！
Look, I'm gonna eat all your pickled seaweed!
(部下)長官！ あれ 本物です!!
本物のﾊﾀ皇子です！
Commissioner... He's the real thing! The real Prince Hata.
どうして あんなところに…｡
What's he doing there?
おぅ これか…｡
松っちゃん砲のｽｲｯﾁ｡
Oh, is this it? Is this the Matsu-blaster firing button?
(部下)いや そうですけど…｡
早く救助しないと大変なことに｡
Uh...yeah... But we have to quickly rescue him.
Huh? Did you just push that? You're kidding! You just pushed it?!
(部下)あれ？ 今 押した？
ｳｿ！ 今 押した!?
いやぁ ５時から
娘のﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰあるからして…｡
I have to be at my daughter's birthday party at five.
(部下)えぇ～っ 止めろ～！
(部下)もうﾑﾘだ!!
What?! We have to stop it!
It can't be stopped!
(じい)あれ？
なんか撃とうとしてない？
Does it look like they're starting to fire?
(ﾊﾀ)ｳｿだろ？ 仮にも皇子だよ!!
You're kidding, right? I am a prince, you know!
やばいって これ！
早く逃げないと…｡
We're in trouble. We gotta get outta here!
(神楽)ｳｶﾞ～ｯ！
それ 私の酢昆布ね!!
That's my pickled seaweed!
(神楽)うりゃあ～！
(星海坊主)神楽!!
Kagura!
うっ！
お前…!?
You did it?!
ったく 食い意地が張ったｶﾞｷだ！
Man, that kid sure gets vicious about food.
親の顔が見てみてえな！ おい｡
Did her parents starve her or something?
(星海坊主)ｵﾚも見てみてえよ｡
You know what I wonder? Did your parents cut out your brain?
お前のような
ﾑﾁｬｸﾁｬな男の親の顔を…｡
Maybe I never had any parents.
男は 下の毛が生えたら もう
ﾃﾒｴでﾃﾒｴを 育てていくもんだ！
(星海坊主)ｸｸｯ… 違いねえ！
That I can believe!
さぁて そろそろ…｡
しまいにしようか！
Now then, shall we?
Let's finish the job.
いくぜ！ おとうさん!!
誰が おとうさんだ～！
Let's do it, dad.
Who're you calling "dad"?!
♪♪～
(隊士たち)あぁっ!!
Look! The alien is...
(隊士)見ろ！ えいりあんが!!
Pops! Stop the attack! There's no need to shoot anymore!
とっつぁん！ 砲撃を止めろ!!
もう撃つ必要はねえ！
泊める？ ふざけるな！
栗子は まだ17歳だぞ｡
Stop? Don't be silly!
Kuriko is still seventeen.
彼氏と２人で
誕生日を祝いたいとは➡
She said she wants to celebrate her party alone with her boyfriend.
ぬかしてやがったが…
あれ 外泊する気だよ｡
But she plans on staying out all night. I absolutely won't allow that.
絶対 許さねえ！
全力で ｼﾞｬﾏしてやる!!
I'll do everything I can to stop it. I'll even dance the Lambada on top of her cake.
ｹｰｷの上で 思いきり
ﾗﾝﾊﾞﾀﾞ 踊ってやる！
｢泊める｣じゃなくて ｢止める｣！
Not stop as in "stop over"! Can't you think of anything else except your daughter?!
ｱﾝﾀ 娘のことしか
考えてねえのか!?
(松平)うるせえな！ どうせもう
今さら中止できねえんだろ!!
Quiet! I can't stop it now, anyway.
(松平)早く逃げろ～！
おっさん 知らないからな!!
Hurry up and get out of there! I won't be responsible for whatever happens to you!!
(松平)おっさんは
一切 責任とりません！
はぁ!? 逃げろったって
どこ逃げろっていうの？
Huh? Run? Where are we supposed to go?
ﾒｶﾞﾈ… ﾒｶﾞﾈ… ﾒｶﾞﾈ…｡
下は ﾑﾘだ！ 上だ 上!!
My glasses... My glasses... My glasses...
Down's no good. Go up. Up!
酢昆布 返せ～！
うぉ～っ!!
Give me back my pickled seaweed!
神楽！ しっかりしろ!!
おい ﾀﾞﾒだって！ 出血が…｡
Kagura, pull yourself together.
Stop it, he's bleeding.
《星海坊主:意識が定まってねえ｡
She's not fully conscious. She broke through the nucleus in this condition?
こんな状態で
核を ぶち破ってきたのか？
この男の声が… 神楽の意識の
底にまで届いたってのか？》
This man's voice reached into the depths of Kagura's subconscious.
あぁ 酢昆布だ…｡
(星海坊主)えっ！
Ah! Pickled seaweed.
(じい/新八)うわっ…｡
ｷﾞｬ～ 何すんの？
おとうさんの大事な昆布が…｡
What're you doing?! Pappy's precious hair!
おい！ 何 食ってんだ!!
出せ！ ﾊｹﾞるぞ!!
Hey! What're you eating?!
Spit it out! You'll go bald! You'll go bald if you eat that!
そんなもん食ったら ﾊｹﾞるぞ～！
あれ？ なに？ この音｡
(砲撃音)
Huh? What's that sound?
(着弾音)
(爆発音)
(部下)目標 消滅を確認｡
Destruction...confirmed.
なんてこった…｡
My...god...
(近藤)まさか あの連中が…｡
Those guys must be...
なっ…｡
How is that possible?
なんだと？
(松平)傘一本で…｡
With just an umbrella...
(松平)あの砲撃を…｡
he blocked the blast.
ぼ… 坊主さん！
B-Bozu-san!
(星海坊主)
ｵﾚも 焼きが まわったようだ｡
Looks like I got a bit fired up myself!
いや 髪の毛も
焼きが まわってるけど…｡
Your hair is on fire, but...
他人を守って くたばるなんざ…｡
Imagine me dying...to save somebody else!
お… おい！
H-Hey!
Bozu-san!
坊主さん！
ﾊｹﾞ！ おい ﾊｹﾞ!!
Baldy! Hey, Baldy!
Bal...I mean... Bozu-san.
ﾊ… じゃない… 坊主さん！
ﾊｹﾞ!!
Baldy...
右側だけ ﾊｹﾞ～！
Baldy, but only on the right!
(ﾍﾘｺﾌﾟﾀｰの飛行音)
(ﾊﾀ)いやぁ 一時は
どうなることかと思ったけどね｡
At one point, I really thought it was the end,
得意の空手で なんとか
乗り切れたみたいな感じみたいな｡
but I prevailed with my exceptional kara-tay skills.
(土方)おぅおぅ…
どうすんだ？ この死骸の山｡
What're we going to do with this mountain of dead alien flesh?
(沖田)ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙも
しばらく運休らしいですぜ｡
The terminal will be out of service for a while, as well.
(土方)上に なに言われるか
わかったもんじゃねえよ｡
No telling what the higher-ups are going to say. That old man, for chrissake...
ったく あのじじい…｡
But that monster was every bit what the rumors said he was.
それにしても
ｳﾜｻどおりのﾊﾞｹﾓﾝだったな｡
ん？
星海坊主だよ 星海坊主…｡
I mean Umibozu... Umibozu.
ｵﾚは 正直
えいりあんなんぞより➡
To tell the truth, I was way more scared of him than the alien.
あのおっさんのほうが
よっぽど恐ろしかったね｡
Really? He didn't look like a monster to me.
そうか？ ｵﾚには ﾔﾂが
ﾊﾞｹﾓﾉになんて見えなかったけどな｡
He just looked like any father, struggling to protect his daughter.
(近藤)娘を守ろうとｼﾞﾀﾊﾞﾀする
ただの人の親に見えたよ｡
(近藤)ｶﾞｷに手をやく
その辺にいる ただの親に…｡
A father just like any other around here, having trouble with his daughter.
(近藤)捜し物とやらは
見つかったのかね？ 星海坊主殿｡
Did you find what you were looking for, Umibozu-dono?
おい 神楽は？
How's Kagura?
(星海坊主)
救護班に 手当てを受けてる｡
She's being treated by the rescue team. Her injury was pretty serious.
けっこうな深手だったんだ｡
Shouldn't you get treated, too?
ｱﾝﾀも手当てしてもらったほうが
いいんじゃねえのか？
I told you, my left arm was a prosthetic from the start.
だから この左腕は
もとから義手だって言ってんだろ｡
新調しなきゃな…｡
腕じゃねえよ 頭だ｡
I just need to get a new one.
Not your arm...your brain.
どういう意味だ？
そういう意味だ｡
What do you mean?
You know what I mean.
そうか ああいう意味か？
殺すぞ｡
Oh, in that case, I'll kill you.
ｸｯ とうとう腕だけじゃなくて
毛まで なくなっちゃったな…｡
Now, I'm missing not only my arm, but my hair, too...
そのうち生えてくるさ｡
腕が生えるかよ｡
It'll grow back in time.
Arms don't grow back.
Not your arm... Your hair.
腕じゃねえよ 頭だ｡
I see... My hair, eh? All you talk about is my hair. I'll kill you.
そうか 頭か…｡ あれ？
お前 頭のことしか
しゃべってねえじゃねえか｡
殺すぞ…｡ まっ でもな➡
But anyway, both of them serve as a lesson to me.
ｺｲﾂは 両方 ｵﾚにとっちゃ
戒めなのかもしれねえよ｡
戒め？
A lesson?
I lost it to my own kid, you see.
ｺｲﾂは ﾃﾒｴのｶﾞｷにやられたのさ｡
Not Kagura. I have an older kid, too.
神楽じゃねえぞ…｡
上に もう一人いてな｡
ｺｲﾂが とんでもねえ性悪でよ…
いや 性悪というか➡
That one's a real bad egg.
No...not bad, let's just say he faithfully carried the blood of the Yato Clan.
夜兎の特性を
忠実に受け継いだというか…｡
闘争本能の塊のようなｶﾞｷでな…｡
He's a kid who's the personification of the fighting spirit.
(星海坊主)はるか昔 夜兎族には➡
A long time ago, the Yato clan had a terrible custom called "Parent Killing."
親殺しという
とんでもねえ風習があったのさ｡
親を超えてなんぼという
野蛮な ならわしが…｡
It was a savage practice where a person's worth was determined by surpassing their parents.
いつの頃か消えた
そんな いにしえの ならわしを➡
These days, that practice has all but disappeared, but he tried to revive it.
野郎は このご時世に
実践しようとしやがったのさ｡
(星海坊主)天下の星海坊主のｸﾋﾞを
とろうとしやがった｡
He tried to take the head of the legendary Umibozu.
驚いたか？ だが 夜兎ってのは
そういう種族なんだよ｡
Surprised? That's what we Yato are like.
そのときにな
ｵﾚも気づいちまったのさ！
When it happened, I suddenly realized...
ｵﾚのｸﾋﾞを狙うｶﾞｷを前にして
止めるのではなく➡
Squaring off with my own son, who was going for my neck...
That I wasn't trying to stop him... I was trying to kill him.
本気で息子を殺そうとしている
ｵﾚの中の血によ…｡
If Kagura hadn't stopped me, I would have murdered him for sure.
(星海坊主)神楽が止めなければ
確実に殺してた｡
あのときのｵﾚを見る
ﾔﾂらの おびえた目は➡
Even now, I can't forget the fear I saw in her eyes.
今でも忘れられねえ｡
そんなことがあってから
ｵﾚは 家に寄りつけなくなってな｡
After that, I couldn't go near my home.
神楽も いつか ﾔﾂのように➡
I was afraid that Kagura would one day seek my life as well.
ｵﾚの命を
狙ってくるんじゃねえかって…｡
そのとき ｵﾚは 自分のなかの獣を
抑えることができるのかって…➡
I was overwhelmed with the fear, that if she did,
不安で しかたなくてな｡
I would not be able to suppress the beast inside of me.
変わる度胸も
信じる度胸もなかった ｵﾚは➡
I didn't have the courage to change, or to trust myself,
so I ran away, leaving young Kagura and her dying mother behind.
幼い神楽と 死にかけた母ちゃんを
残して 逃げ回った｡
家族を壊すのが怖かった｡
I was afraid of destroying my family, but in the end, not a trace of my family remains.
結果 家族なんて
跡形もなく消えちまったよ｡
神楽に
ｵﾚと同じ思いをさせまいと➡
I came all this way, because I didn't want Kagura to go through the same thing I did.
こんなところまで
ｱｲﾂを追いかけてきちまった｡
But I almost repeated the same mistake.
ｵﾚは また同じことを
繰り返そうとしていたんだな｡
(星海坊主)お前に言われて
ﾊｯとなったよ｡
When you told me, it hit me.
あのとき ｵﾚを止めてくれたのも➡
It was Kagura who stopped me then, and it was always Kagura who supported me.
いつも ｵﾚを支えてくれたのも
神楽だ｡
そんな神楽を 何一つ
信じちゃいなかったんだ｡
That's how she is, and yet I couldn't even trust her one bit.
自分を見て
神楽を見たつもりでいた｡
I thought I saw myself in Kagura. But Kagura and I are different. She's...
ｵﾚと神楽は 違う｡
ｱｲﾂは… ｱｲﾂは ｵﾚなんかより➡
She's a lot stronger than I am.
ずっと 強いﾔﾂなんだよ｡
But I-I'm a total failure as a father.
(星海坊主)それを ｵﾚってﾔﾂは…｡
完全に 父親失格だ｡
No...maybe I'm the only one who thinks I'm a father.
いや 親父と思ってるのは
ｵﾚだけで➡
ｱｲﾂは ｵﾚみたいなﾔﾂのこと➡
親父とさえ
思ってねえのかもしれねえな｡
Maybe she doesn't even think of me as her father.
A letter...
手紙｡
なんかいつも ｺｿｺｿ書いてたぜ｡
She always wrote them in secret.
Since you had no permanent address, they were always sent back to my place.
ｱﾝﾀ 住所不定みたいだから➡
いつも
うちに返されてきたけどな｡
渡す機会があるかもって➡
I secretly kept all of them in my closet hoping if I ever got the chance to hand them to you...
内緒で全部
押し入れに取ってあるが➡
今は これしかねえや｡
This is the only one I have right now.
Oh, and don't worry, I'd never do anything so crass as to read them.
おっと 安心しな｡
中身を見るような
ﾔﾎﾞなﾏﾈは してねえよ｡
I figured you're not the type...to read this and go nuts about it.
ついでにｱﾝﾀも これ見て
ｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞ言うほど ﾔﾎﾞじゃねえよな｡
じゃあな！
おい｡
See you later.
Hey!
I don't know all the details, but...
細けえことは よくわからねえや｡
けど
自分を想ってくれる親がいて➡
If you have a parent who cares about you, what more do you need?
他に 何がいるよ｡
I wish I had one... A family like yours.
ｵﾚは 欲しかったよ｡
ｱﾝﾀみてえな家族が｡
Gin...
お前…｡
Ironic, ain't it?
皮肉なもんだな｡
ﾎﾝﾄに大事なもんってのは➡
How the people who don't have things...usually understand them better than the ones who do.
持ってるﾔﾂより
持ってねえﾔﾂのほうが➡
知ってるもんさ｡
So...cherish her... Okay?
だからよぉ ｱｲﾂのこと➡
大事にしてやってくれよな｡
♪♪～
ん？
言っとくけどね➡
Let me make this clear. I'm staying at the Odd Jobs for good.
ﾎﾞｸは ずっと
万事屋にいますからね｡
家族と
思ってくれていいですからね！
You can think of me as family.
はぁ…｡
Didn't he say he was quitting?
やめるとか言ってなかったっけ？
(星海坊主)ﾌﾌｯ ｢大事にしろ｣か…｡
Cherish her, huh?
(星海坊主)お～い
聞いてるか 神楽｡
Hey! Are you listening, Kagura?
そういうことだから お父さん➡
That's the deal. From now on... Daddy will cherish you.
これから お前を
大事にすることになったから｡
So be happy, okay?
だから 元気でやれよ｡
Pappy! Why...
(神楽)ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ 待って｡
Wait, Pappy!
待って ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ！
♪♪～
(神楽)｢拝啓 お父さん｡
しばらく会っていませんが➡
Dear Father,
I haven't seen you in a while. Are you well? I'm doing fine.
元気ですか？ 私は元気です｡
私は今
侍という 不思議な連中が住む➡
Right now, I am living in a city called Edo with some strange people called samurai.
江戸という街に住んでいます｡
They are truly strange creatures.
彼らは
本当に不思議な生き物です｡
Even though they're usually all weak, hopeless and pathetic,
ふだんは みんな 弱くて ｼｮﾎﾞくて
ﾀﾞﾒ野郎ばかりなのに➡
いざというときは
武士道という信念で➡
when it really counts, they call on some idea called "Bushido" and become these tough, noble warriors.
自分を たたき上げ➡
絶対に折れない
屈強な戦士になるのです｡
夜兎も侍も みんな変わりません｡
And they have something in common with the Yato. They're all fighting against themselves.
みんな 自分と戦っています｡
ここでなら
私は変われる気がします｡
I think if I stay here I can change.
きっと 自分に負けない自分に
なれると思うのです｡
I think I can become a person who doesn't give in to herself.
そうしたら お父さん
きっと 私を➡
If I do change, Pappy... I want you to take me with you on your travels.
一緒に
旅に連れて行ってくださいね｡
お父さんと一緒に
宇宙を まわって➡
My dream is to travel through the universe with you...and become the top alien hunter in the galaxy.
宇宙一の えいりあんはんたーに
なるのが➡
私の夢です｡ 神楽より｣
Love, Kagura.
I'll be waiting, Kagura.
待ってるぞ 神楽｡
♪♪～
[The Look]
[Preview]
Next time, now that Kagura is gone, I'll be the heroine!
[The Figure]
[The Character]
["Make Characters So Anybody Can Tell Who They Are by Just Their Silhouettes"]
[A fight breaks out over who will be the next heroine.]
[Otae vs. Sachan vs. Catherine, and even Otose!]
(ﾔﾔｺﾏ)ﾔｺ！
(鼻歌)
ﾔﾔｺﾏ ｾﾚﾅを起こしてきて｡
さっき一度起こしたんだけど
全然 下りてこないのよ｡
ﾔｺ｡